[Music]
the american journal of clinical
nutrition
is the highest ranked peer-reviewed
scientific journal in nutrition
that should tell you a lot about the
field since it's published by the
american society of nutrition whose
sustaining partners include
the sugar association
candy bar and soda companies the corn
syrup people and the meat dairy and egg
industries and this is the highest
ranked nutrition journal
the fact that the national cattlemen's
beef association is a sustaining partner
may help explain their publication of
this article
imagine you're in the pocket of big beef
and big pig
how could you possibly pull off a study
showing that eating red meat does not
negatively influence cardiovascular
disease risk factors
a meta-analysis of randomized controlled
trials showing that eating more versus
less red meat
does not
influence cholesterol or blood pressure
doctors barnard and willett pointed out
the fatal flaw in their editorial the
misuse of meta-analysis in nutrition
research by asking the question compared
to what
of the 39 trials that they had chosen on
ldl cholesterol nearly 90 percent of
them were just swapping one meat for
another comparing red meat to white meat
they were using chicken control diets
or
fish control diets and we know that when
it comes to cholesterol the impact of
beef consumption is just as bad as fish
or poultry and so that's how they pulled
it off they just swapped meats
that's like publishing a study saying
total twinkie intake does not negatively
influence risk factors by switching
twinkies with ding-dongs those
randomized to zero twinkies didn't do
any better
yeah because now they were eating
ding-dongs
it's a classic drug industry trick
testing your drug against something
known to be terrible
whereas if you swap out meat for
plant-based meats plant-based sausages
plant-based chicken patties and veggie
dogs you end up with significantly lower
cholesterol
well
you say there's less saturated fat in
plant-based meats but even
independent of saturated fat content you
end up with higher ldl cholesterol with
red meat or white meat any kind of meat
compared to non-meat protein sources the
researchers conclude that this is
keeping with recommendations promoting
diets with a high proportion of
plant-based food but based on
cholesterol effects white meat like
chicken and turkey is just as bad as red
and fish
may be even worse
though what they often did is try to
standardize the saturated fat content by
adding like butter but at the same
saturated fat content fish
appears to be worse than beef and
chicken just as bad as beef yet plant
protein sources like legumes
soy and nuts so beans split peas
chickpeas lentils soybeans and nuts did
better
switch out a single serving of even lean
beef with the same amount of calories of
nuts or soy beans and you can lower ldl
bad cholesterol a key risk factor for
the number one killer of men and women
in the united states and around much of
the world
but wait
is that why a single serving of nuts a
day is associated with a 22 reduction in
the risk of premature death
why millions of deaths every year may be
attributable to inadequate nut intake
maybe the benefit is just because
they're eating nuts instead of meat
no
the drop of heart attacks amongst more
frequent nut eaters is just as strong or
even stronger among
vegetarians
the reduced mortality associated with
nut consumption is independent of health
condition
it's not just health nuts eating nuts in
fact in a comparison of a dozen
different food groups nuts beat out even
vegetables when it came to a lower risk
of premature death
[Music]
you